# **Blanca Mendizabal Perello**

Full-stack software developer recently graduated from Makers Academy, Europe's leading web development bootcamp. I'm looking for a junior developer position in a company where I can make an impact and also grow professionally.

+1 (206) 698 6782 • blanca.mendizabal.perello@gmail.com • Blog • GitHub • LinkedIn • Twitter

## **Personal projects**

Safe Water - React, Jest, Enzyme, Node.js, Express, PostgreSQL - Ongoing

Single-page app that helps users know the quality of drinking water in their area. The responsive user interface in the front-end communicates with a back-end that retrieves data from a database, and highlights dangerous levels for each contaminant.

Flickr Gallery - React, Jest, Enzyme, Sinatra - 5 days

Single-page app with a front-end that queries the Flickr API for cute photos through a proxy that deals with authentication and CORS.

Flashcards - React, Jest, Enzyme, Ruby on Rails, RSpec, GitHub OAuth, PostgreSQL - 45 days

Self-service tool for users to learn through spaced repetition. It allows them to create, edit, and delete flashcards. The front-end makes requests to an API in the back-end, fetching tags and flashcards for the logged in user.

CSS playground - React, Jest, HTML5, CSS3 - 10 days

Final project at Makers Academy. A live-editing HTML and CSS tool that allows users with no coding experience to create basic website drafts, and download the code.

#### Skills

**Project Management** – I've shown strong ability breaking projects into smaller tasks while working at Little Bee Community. I managed a project in Africa, creating a three-year timeline that included monthly and weekly tasks, cost tracking, and list of suppliers. This structured workflow made it easier to deliver the project on time and on budget.

**Adaptability** – For the last five years I have been experiencing big changes in my life, and I managed to successfully overcome them by focusing on my strengths and abilities. My last challenge, a career change, started one year ago when I began learning HTML, CSS and JavaScript by myself. I then decided to join Makers Academy, a 12-week bootcamp where I learnt Ruby, Rails, Node, and React, to name a few technologies.

**Communication and Collaboration** – My colleagues at Makers highlight my empathy, patience, and ability to explain concepts clearly as my main skills. For example, on one specially challenging week I noticed that my colleague was struggling with understanding how a Node app works. I helped her analyze the project's structure and data flow. By the end of the day we managed to have a server up and running!

**Design and User Experience** – I'm passionate about crafting attractive and user-friendly interfaces for every project I work on. I have taught myself CSS, Bootstrap, Photoshop, InDesign, and Illustrator. I have used these skills to create appealing and usable apps in personal projects, and marketing materials for Little Bee Community and Battle McCarthy.

## **Experience**

Sustainability Consultant at Little Bee Community (London, UK) Oct 2013 - Aug 2016

Led a wide range of projects locally and abroad, ensuring goals were met on time and on budget. I co-designed and launched an urban vertical farming project, gaining buy-in from a range of local stakeholders, managed and mentored a team of interns, and played a lead role in developing impact frameworks and reports.

Agricultural Engineer at Battle McCarthy (London, UK) Jan 2013 - Oct 2013

Responsible for urban agriculture R&D. I worked with five other people, developing agricultural strategies to maximize food production inside buildings using hydroponic systems.

Environmental Engineer at Aqualogy (AGBAR group) (Madrid, Spain) Sep 2011 – Sep 2012

Responsible for conducting compliance checks to enforce European laws regarding water treatment. I also designed a working methodology for the analysis of biological quality parameters of Spanish rivers.

### Education

### Software Development Self-Training Jan 2016 - Ongoing

I'm improving my software development skills using online sources and books. Currently I'm working on side projects focusing on:

- · Single-page apps using React
- · APIs using Express, Sinatra, or Ruby on Rails
- Algorithms and data structures

Onsite Software Development Bootcamp at Makers Academy (London, UK) Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

Highly-selective 12-week full-time program (and 4-week pre-course), emphasizing:

- Front-end development (JavaScript, React)
- Back-end development (Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Node.js)
- · Pair-programming
- Test-driven development
- · Object-oriented design
- · Agile methodologies

M.Sc. Environmental Engineering and Management at EOI Business School (Madrid, Spain) 2010 -- 2011

Master thesis "Development of an Environmental Management System under the European EMAS Regulation".

M.Sc Agricultural Engineering at Technical University of Madrid (Madrid, Spain) 2000 - 2008

My final year project, "Iberian Pig Value Chain Analysis", received an outstanding qualification.

### Other information

- English (professional working proficiency), Spanish (native).
- I love making my own bread, and photography.